

Domenico Camasta

✓ domenicocamasta@gmail.com 📞 3701522690 🔮 Via F. Baracca 8 🛗 29/12/1983

■ Italian

♣ He/Him ★ portfolio.devcrumbs.com ♠ d-cmst

Profile

I'm a software developer with over 10 years of experience building web applications using technologies like Python, JavaScript, React, and Node. is. My expertise includes designing and implementing RESTful APIs and optimizing database queries for performance.

Professional Experience

Developer, *UserTesting* □

2018 - 12/2022

Creating and executing usability tests to evaluate the ease of use, efficiency, and overall user experience of software products: designing test plans, coding test scripts, recruiting test participants, and analyzing test results.

UK | Germany | Remote

Developer, Appen Ltd Chatbot software development. 2020 - 2022

Project Manager, *UniD Formazione* □

2015 - 2018

Remote

Development, deployment and system administration for the company web applications.

Borgo Maggiore, RSM

Teacher, MIUR □

2011 - 2014

Mathematics/Logic teacher for high school and university students.

Verona, Italy

Languages

Italian Native

English

TOEFL 2020

Education

PhD, Università "La Sapienza"

2007 - 2010

PhD Program in Mathematical Logic | Thesis title: "A two-dimensional semantics for

Rome, Italy

natural language formalization"

Master Degree, Università Degli Studi di Genova

2002 - 2007

Italian Master Degree (Laurea Magistrale) in Mathematics

Genova, Italy

Certificates

TOEFL

Test date: 2020

Score: 98/120 (Advanced)

PCAP - Certified Associate in Python Programming

ID: 383260354

Validation: 338962730

Score: 92%

Projects

AGReATWine, *Contributor* □

2020 - present

Creation of a database of Italian wines included in DOCG appellations, evaluated by the three main national wine guides

KDE, Contributor, Member ☑

2005 - present

Code, designs and translations for many desktop applications and web applications from the KDE ecosystem.

ArchLinux, *Package mantainer* □

2005 - present

Arch Linux is a Linux distribution that tries to Keep It Simple

GSConnect, Contributor □

Complete implementation of KDE Connect especially for GNOME Shell.

InvoicePlane, *Contributor* □

A self-hosted open source application for managing your invoices, clients and payments.

RAMP, Contributor

Ramp is a python library for rapid prototyping of machine learning solutions. It's a light-weight pandas-based machine learning framework pluggable with existing python machine learning and statistics tools.

Wiki.js, *Patch contributor* □

Wiki.js is a modern and powerful wiki app built on Node.js

Publications

Collana UnidTest, Libri per la preparazione dei test di ammissione universitari 🛭